I am a graduate student at the University of Arizona where I work with Dr. Betsy Arnold. I am interested in addressing the interplay of host genotype, environment, and fungal
symbiont communities in order to better understand the effect of local adaptation on host performance and wider ecosystem processes.

For my dissertation, I am looking at how abiotic and biotic factors related to climate change shape communities of fungal symbionts associated with Ponderosa pine (Pinus ponderosa subsp. scopulorum) across isolated montane forests in central and southern Arizona. We are focusing on ectomycorrhizal fungi and foliar endophytic fungi in order to link above- and below-ground processes. I am particularly interested in looking at community disassembly and local variation across these communities in order to understand how this may affect the outcome of these plant-fungal symbioses. 

I received a B.S. in Botany from Oregon State University in 2014, before coming to Dr. Arnold’s lab for a M.S. in fall 2014 and then remaining for a PhD in fall 2016. 

Please feel free to contact me at eabowman@email.arizona.edu.
